Guide to the Duke Endowment Archives, 1902-2018 and undated, bulk 1925-2006 RL.00332
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Rural Church Division Series (RESTRICTED), 1918-2006 and undated, 152 boxes
  - Building Grant Files Subseries, 1920-2006 and undated
    - Westview Church, Pendler County, 1968-1969, 1980 (Box RCD 118)
    - Westwood Church, Wayne County, 1967-1974, 1989-1991 (Box RCD 118)
    - Weyman Church, Columbus County, 1952 (Box RCD 118)
    - Wharton Church, Beaufort County, 1946-1957, n.d (Box RCD 118)
    - Whitaker's Church, Nash County, 1953-1955 and undated (Box RCD 118)
    - Whitaker's Chapel, Surry County, 1956-1957 (Box RCD 118)
    - White Oak Church, Bertie County, 1955-1959 (Box RCD 118)
    - White Oak Church, Bladen County, 1932-1935 (Box RCD 118)
    - White Oak Church, Nash County, 1959 and undated (Box RCD 118)
    - White Plains Church, Wake County, 1962-1964, 2 folders (Box RCD 118)
    - White Rock Church, Wilkes County, 1960-1976, 2 folders (Box RCD 118)
    - Whitley Memorial Church, Jones County, 1973 (Box RCD 118)
    - Whitnell Church, Caldwell County, 1926-1935 and undated (Box RCD 118)
    - Whittier Church, Swain County, 1946-1949 (Box RCD 118)
    - Wightman Church, Anson County, 1943-1969 and undated (Box RCD 118)
    - Wilkesboro Church, Wilkes County, 1945-1949 and undated (Box RCD 118)
    - Williamston's Chapel, Iredell County, 1937-1938, 1968-1970 and undated, 2 folders (Box RCD 118)
    - Williston Church, Carteret County, 1949-1950 and undated (Box RCD 118)
    - Windom Church, Yancey County, 1961-1966 and undated, 2 folders (Box RCD 118)
    - Wingate Church, Union County, 1952 (Box RCD 118)
    - Windsor Church, Bladen County, 1937-1938 and undated (Box RCD 118)
    - Winterville Church, Pitt County, 1932-1935 and undated (Box RCD 118)
    - Winton Church, Hertford County, 1927-1930 (Box RCD 118)
    - Withers Chapel, Stokes County, 1982-1984 (Box RCD 119)
    - Wolf Mountain Church, Jackson County, 1931-1932 (Box RCD 119)
    - Woodfin Church, Buncombe County, undated (Box RCD 119)
    - Woodington Church, Lenoir County, 1936-1941 and undated (Box RCD 119)
    - Woodland Church, Duplin County, 1936-1964, 1984-1987 and undated, 2 folders (Box RCD 119)
    - Woodland Church, Northampton County, 1925-1938, 1954, 1981-1983 and undated, 3 folders (Box RCD 119)
    - Woodland Church, Perquimans County, 1956-1962, 2 folders (Box RCD 119)
    - Woodleaf Church, Rowan County, 1942-1943 (Box RCD 119)
    - Woodsdale Church, Person County, 1927-1928 and undated (Box RCD 119)
    - Woodside Church, Harnett County, 1972-1982 (Box RCD 119)
    - Wrightsboro Church, New Hanover County, 1962 (Box RCD 119)
    - Wrightsville Beach Church, New Hanover County, 1947-1967 and undated (Box RCD 119)
    - Yadkin College Church, Davidson County, 1944-1960 (Box RCD 119)
    - Yadkinville Church, Yadkin County, 1933-1950 and undated (Box RCD 119)
    - Yanceyville Church, Caswell County, 1941-1944 (Box RCD 119)
    - Yaupon Beach Church, Brunswick County, 1959 and undated (Box RCD 119)
    - Yelverton Church, Wayne County, 1947 and undated (Box RCD 119)
    - Young's Chapel, Avery County, 1927 and undated (Box RCD 119)
    - Youngsville Church, Franklin County, 1927-1928, n.d (Box RCD 119)
    - Zebulon Church, Wake County, 1936-1950 and undated (Box RCD 119)
    - Zion Church, Ashe County, 1961-1964 and undated, 2 folders (Box RCD 119)
    - Zion Church, Brunswick County, 1925-1958, 1988-1990 and undated, 2 folders (Box RCD 119)
    - Zion Church, Burke County, 1940-1951 (Box RCD 119)
    - Zion Church, Chatham County, 1959-1966 and undated (Box RCD 120)
    - Zion Church, Columbus County, 1940-1946 and undated (Box RCD 120)
    - Zion Church, Davie County, 1960 (Box RCD 120)
    - Zion Church, Gates County, 1925-1970 (Box RCD 120)
    - Zion Church, Northampton County, 1949-1967, 2 folders (Box RCD 120)
    - Zion Church, Richmond County, 1928-1969 and undated (Box RCD 120)
    - Zion Church, Rowan County, 1958-1958 (Box RCD 120)
    - Zion Church, Surry County, 1948-1950 (Box RCD 120)
    - Zion Church, Union County, 1940-1958 (Box RCD 120)
    - Zion Church, Warren County, 1934-1955 (Box RCD 120)
    - Zora Chapel, Granville County, 1981-1982 (Box RCD 120)
    - Churches Assisted, 1920:
      - North Carolina Conference (Box RCD 120)
      - Western North Carolina Conference (Box RCD 120)
    - Churches Assisted (by Circuit), 1920-1929
      - Advance - Burlington (Box RCD 120)
      - Carver's Creek - Durham (Box RCD 120)
      - East Burlington - Gumneck (Box RCD 120)
      - Hanes - Clemons - Kitty Hawk (Box RCD 120)
      - Lake Junaluska - Murfreesboro - Winton (Box RCD 120)
      - New Hope - Rutherfordton (Box RCD 120)
      - Sandy Mush - Swansboro (Box RCD 120)
      - Table Rock - Zebulon (Box RCD 120)
    - Statistics, miscellaneous, 1926, 1932, 1934-1935, and undated (Box RCD 120)
  - Church Maintenance Files Subseries, 1924-2006 and undated
    Includes appropriations, applications, recommendations for funding, and questionnaires about charges.
    Arranged with appropriations files first, then files for North Carolina and Western North Carolina charges, then alphabetically by names of charges.
    - Applications for Aid, 1951-1953 (Box RCD 121)
    - Applications Summaries, 1962,and undated, 2 folders (Box RCD 121)
    - Appropriations, 1924-1934, 8 folders (Box RCD 121)
    - Appropriations, 1935-1941, 7 folders (Box RCD 122)
    - Appropriations, 1942-1950, 11 folders (Box RCD 123)
    - Appropriations, 1966-1997 (Box RCD 124)
      - Duke University, 1966-1997, 3 folders (Box RCD 124)
      - Building and Architectural Service Grants, 1974-1978 (Box RCD 124)
      - Building Appropriations (C & 4), 1976, 2 folders (Box RCD 124)
      - Regular, In-Service, and Special Projects: Parish Development Grants, 1976, 2 folders (Box RCD 124)
      - Students and Assistants (C & 4), 1976, 2 folders (Box RCD 124)
      - Regular, In-Service, Special Projects, Parish Development Grants, 1977, 2 folders (Box RCD 125)
      - Student and Assistant Pastors (C & 4), 1977, 2 folders (Box RCD 125)
      - Building Appropriations (C & 4), 1978 (Box RCD 125)
      - Regular Pastors, In-Service, Special Projects, Parish Development Grants, Church and Community Study Grants, 1978 (2 folders) (Box RCD 125)
      - Student and Assistant Pastors (C & 4), 1978, 2 folders (Box RCD 125)
      - Building Grants, 1979-1993 (Box RCD 125)
      - Regular Pastors, In-Service, Special Projects, Parish Development Grants, Church and Community Study Grants (C & 4), 1979, 2 folders (Box RCD 126)
      - Student and Assistant Pastors (C & 4), 1979, 2 folders (Box RCD 126)
      - Regular Pastors, In-Service, Special Projects, Parish Development Grants, S/A, Church and Community Study Grants (C & 4), 1980, 2 folders (Box RCD 126)
      - Regular Pastors, In-Service, Special Projects, Parish Development Grants, S/A, Church and Community Study Grants (C & 4), 1981, 2 folders (Box RCD 126)
      - Student and Assistant Pastors, Student Interns (C & 4), 1981 (Box RCD 126)
    - Appropriations, Recommendations of the Local Committee, 1927-1949, 6 folders (Box RCD 127)
    - Appropriations Summary, undated (Box RCD 127)
    - North Carolina Conference
      - Bishop Carl P. Minnick Jr., 1977-1997 (Box RCD 127)
      - Board of Missions, Ethnic Minorities Study, 1986 Apr. (Box RCD 127)
      - Building of Ethnic Minority Parsonages, 1978 (Box RCD 127)
      - Cabinet Meeting, 1980 Sept. (Box RCD 127)
      - Church Numbers, undated (Box RCD 127)
      - Commission on Equitable Salaries, 1979-1988 (Box RCD 127)
      - Committee on Continuing Education, 1974-1990 (Box RCD 128)
      - Committee to Study Cost of Parish Travel, 1974-1975 (Box RCD 128)
      - Data on Per Capita Giving, 1979 (Box RCD 128)
      - District Board of Church Location and Building, 1979 (Box RCD 128)
      - Division of Missions, 1974-1994, 3 folders (Box RCD 128)
      - General Correpondence, 1978-1998 (Box RCD 128)
      - RAFI, USA Economic Development, 2001-2005 (Box RCD 150)
      - Research Project- Mount Sylvan, 1971-1976 (Box RCD 128)
      - Research Project-Wilmington District, 1971-1973 (Box RCD 128)
      - Survey, 1955 (Box RCD 128)
      - Task Force on Charge Realignment, 1986-1992 (Box RCD 128)
      - Trends in Population and Membership, 1981 (Box RCD 128)
    - North Carolina Conference (by Charge), 1926-1937: (Box RCD 129)
      - Ahoskie - Aulander (Box RCD 129)
      - Bahama - Bynum (Box RCD 129)
      - Caledonia - Durham (Box RCD 129)
      - East Roxboro - Grimesland (Box RCD 129)
      - Halifax - Kitty Hawk (Box RCD 129)
      - Laurel Hill - Lumberton (Box RCD 129)
      - Magnolia - Murfreesboro-Winton (Box RCD 129)
      - Newport - Oxford (Box RCD 129)
      - Pamlico - Princeton (Box RCD 129)
      - Riverside-Bridgeton - Roxboro-Longhurst (Box RCD 129)
      - Scott's Hill - Swansboro (Box RCD 129)
      - Tabor City - Youngsville (Box RCD 129)
    - North Carolina Conference (by Charge), 1961-1970: (Box RCD 130)
      - Apex-Williston-Smyra, 2 folders (Box RCD 130)
      - Leasburg-Salem-Walstonburg-Tabernacle (Box RCD 130)
      - Mt. Zion- Williston-Smyrna (Box RCD 130)
      - Mt Tirzah- Williston-Smyrna (Box RCD 130)
      - Mt. Zion- Sandy Plain (Box RCD 130)
      - Stonewall-Williston-Smyrna (Box RCD 130)
    - North Carolina Conference (by Charge), 2001-2004: (Box RCD 149)
      - Currituck, 2 folders (Box RCD 149)
    - North Carolina, Charge Realignment (Box RCD 130)
      - Edgecombe County Charge Study, 1974-1979, 2 folders (Box RCD 130)
      - New Hope-Woodland Charge, 1991 (Box RCD 130)
      - Northampton Charge Study, 1975 (Box RCD 130)
      - Sampson County, 1981 (Box RCD 130)
      - Task Force on Charge Realignment, 1975-1979 (Box RCD 130)
      - West View-Jordan's Chapel, 1981 (Box RCD 130)
    - North Carolina Conference, Urban Churches (by District)
      - Burlington District, 1975-1993, 6 folders (Box RCD 130)
      - Durham District, 1987-1999, 2 folders (Box RCD 130)
      - Durham District, 2002-2006 (Box RCD 149)
      - Elizabeth City District, 1975-1980, 2 folders (Box RCD 130)
      - Fayetteville District, 1974-1987, 6 folders (Box RCD 130)
      - Goldsboro District, 1986-1988, 2 folders (Box RCD 131)
      - Greenville District, 1986-1996, 3 folders (Box RCD 131)
      - New Bern District, 1980-1991, 4 folders (Box RCD 131)
      - Raleigh District, 1974-2001, 12 folders (Box RCD 131)
      - Rockingham District, 1980-1987, 4 folders (Box RCD 131)
      - Rocky Mount District, 1985-1993, 4 folders (Box RCD 131)
      - Sanford District, 1991-1994, 2 folders (Box RCD 132)
      - Wilmington District, 1974-1992, 5 folders (Box RCD 132)
    - Western North Carolina Conference
      - 1926 Apr.-1933 Oct. and undated, 13 folders (Box RCD 132)
      - 1933 Nov.-1939 Jan. and undated, 9 folders (Box RCD 133)
      - Annual Conference Reports, 2000 (Box RCD 133)
      - Bishop L. Scott Allen, 1978-1995 (Box RCD 133)
      - Cabinet Meeting, 1980 (Box RCD 133)
      - Congregational Development, 1993 (Box RCD 133)
      - Economic Development, Waynesville District, 2000-2001 (Box RCD 151)
      - General Correspondence, 1977-1998 (Box RCD 133)
      - IFRAA Meeting, 2002 (Box RCD 151)
      - Research Project-East Lincoln County, 1971 (Box RCD 133)
      - Research Project-North Davidson County, 1971-1972 (Box RCD 133)
      - Research Project-Surry County, 1971-1972 (Box RCD 133)
      - Town and Country, 1979, 1988 (Box RCD 133)
      - Work Area on Parish and Community, 1975-1976 (Box RCD 133)
    - Western North Carolina Conference (by Charge), 1926-1937:
      - Advance - Avery (Box RCD 133)
      - Baskerville - Burnsville (Box RCD 133)
      - Candler - Creston (Box RCD 133)
      - Danbury - Dudley Shoals (Box RCD 133)
      - Elk Mountain - Elmwood (Box RCD 134)
      - Fairview - Franklin (Box RCD 134)
      - Gibsonville - Guilford (Box RCD 134)
      - Hayesville - Hudson (Box RCD 134)
      - Jonathan - Junaluska (Box RCD 134)
      - Landis - Lincoln (Box RCD 134)
      - McDowell - Murphy (Box RCD 134)
      - New Hope - Old Fort (Box RCD 134)
      - Pfeiffer - Ruffin (Box RCD 134)
      - Sakyda-Tryon - Swannanoa (Box RCD 134)
      - Table Rock - Woodleaf (Box RCD 134)
    - Western North Carolina Conference (by Charge), 1961-1970:
      - Andrews-Weaverville Ct. (Box RCD 134)
      - Andrews-Walstonburg-Tabernacle (Box RCD 134)
      - Bald Creek-West Jefferson, 2 folders (Box RCD 134)
      - Andrews-Union (Box RCD 134)
      - Andrews-Taylorsville (Box RCD 134)
      - Andrews-Stony Point (Box RCD 134)
    - Western North Carolina Conference (by Charge), 2001-2003:
      - Friendship=Shady Grove (Box RCD 134)
    - Western North Carolina Conference, Urban Churches (by District) (Box RCD 135)
      - Albemarle District, 1983-1991, 3 folders (Box RCD 135)
      - Asheville District, 1967-1994, 10 folders (Box RCD 135)
      - Charlotte District, 1977-1995, 11 folders (Box RCD 135)
      - Gastonia District, 1978-1995, Folders 1-6 of 13 (Box RCD 135)
      - Gastonia District, 1978-1995, Folders 7-13 of 13 (Box RCD 136)
      - Greensboro District, 1976-1992, 6 folders (Box RCD 136)
      - High Point District, 1978-1993, 6 folders (Box RCD 136)
      - Lexington District, 1986-1993, 4 folders (Box RCD 136)
      - Lexington District 2000-2004 (Box RCD 149)
      - Marion District, 1985-1999, 6 folders (Box RCD 136)
      - Northeast District, 1988-1998, 4 folders (Box RCD 136)
      - North Wilkesboro, 1988-1998, Folders 1-3 of 6 (Box RCD 136)
      - North Wilkesboro, 1988-1998, Folders 4-6 of 6 (Box RCD 137)
      - Salisbury District, 1976-1997, 7 folders (Box RCD 137)
      - Statesville District, 1977-1996, 6 folders (Box RCD 137)
      - Waynesville District, 1987-1989, 2 folders (Box RCD 137)
      - Winston-Salem District, 1981-1999, 8 folders (Box RCD 137)
  - Miscellaneous Subseries, 1926-2001 and undated
    Includes miscellaneous files for the Church Architect Program; a self-study conference; the Methodist Episcopal Church, South, Rural Work Commission; and also the reports, minutes, and related documents of the Rural Church Committee.
    Arranged alphabetically, then chronologically therein.
    - Architects, correspondence and lists, 2 folders (Box RCD 137)
    - Bishop's Advisory Committee
      - General, 1976-1979 (Box RCD 137)
      - Review Subcommittee, 1977-1979 (Box RCD 137)
      - Building Grants Subcommittee, 1978-1979 (Box RCD 137)
      - Maintenance and Operation Subcommittee, 1978-1979 (Box RCD 137)
    - Bishop's Seminar Committee, 1984-1988 (Box RCD 137)
    - Church Architect Program, 1928-1932, 2 folders (Box RCD 138)
    - Church Plans and Photos (Box RCD 138)
    - Committees on Church Architecture
      - Bishop's Committee on Church Architecture--Joint Meetings and North Carolina Conference Meetings, 1957-1964, 2 folders (Box RCD 138)
      - Bishop's Committee on Church Architecture, General--Western North Carolina Conference, 1964-1972 (Box RCD 138)
      - Randolph E. DuMont Design Program, 1961-1975, 8 folders (Box RCD 138)
      - Church Architecture, Committee on (includes negatives and photographs), 1969, 1972 (Box RCD 138)
      - North Carolina Conference, 1972, 1979, 2 folders (Box RCD 138)
      - Joint Committee, 1977-1979, 3 folders (Box RCD 138)
    - Duke Endowment Building Brochure, Revision, 1962 (Box RCD 138)
    - Durham Committee, 1959-1967, 2 folders (Box RCD 138)
    - Financial reports, statements, and records of payment (Box RCD 139)
      - Donations Made by the Duke Endowment for Building Aid to Rural Churches in NC and WNC Conferences, 1926-1958 (Box RCD 139)
      - Duke Endowment Assistance, 1960-1961 (Box RCD 139)
      - Duke Endowment Fund, Rural Church Division, 1945-1954 (Box RCD 139)
      - Payments Duke Endowment Building Program, 1959-1969, 2 folders (Box RCD 139)
      - Proof Sheets for Annual Report and Schedule 5, 2000-2001, 2 folders (Box RCD 139)
      - Record of checks sent by N.Y. Office to Mr. W. O. Petty, 1968-1973 (Box RCD 139)
    - Methodist Episcopal Church, South:
      - Rural Work Commission, 1934-1935 and undated, 2 folders (Box RCD 139)
    - North Carolina State College School of Design Project, 1959-1963, 3 folders (Box RCD 139)
    - Rural Church Committee:
      - History and General Information
        - Annual Report, 1992-1999 (Box RCD 139)
        - Basis of Operation, 1949-1958 (Box RCD 139)
        - Duke Endowment Study-10 years, 1951-1953 (Box RCD 140)
        - Fiftieth Anniversary Self-Study Conference, 1977 (Box RCD 140)
        - Friendly Suit, 1971-1972 (Box RCD 140)
        - General Conference, 1980 (Box RCD 140)
        - History and General Information, 1960-1998, 3 folders (Box RCD 140)
        - Memorabilia, 1988-1991 (Box RCD 140)
        - Methodist Foundation, Inc, Brochure, 1962 (Box RCD 140)
        - Options for a New United Methodist Church in the Kildaire Farms Development, 1976 (Box RCD 140)
        - Policy and Procedures Manual, 1980 (Box RCD 140)
        - Rural Church Building Program, 1966 and undated (Box RCD 140)
        - The Rural Church Re-visited, by M. Wilson Nesbitt, 1972 (Box RCD 140)
      - Meetings, 1956-1971, Folders 1-3 of 16 (Box RCD 140)
      - Meetings, 1956-1971, Folders 4-14 of 16 (Box RCD 141)
      - Meetings, 1956-1971, Folders 15-16 of 16 (Box RCD 142)
      - Reports, 1950-1990, Folders 1-17 of 33 (Box RCD 142)
      - Reports, 1950-1990, Folders 18-33 of 33 (Box RCD 143)
      - Minutes and Related Documents, 1926-1990, Folders 1-7 of 33 (Box RCD 144)
      - Minutes and Related Documents, 1926-1990, Folders 8-20 of 33 (Box RCD 145)
      - Minutes and Related Documents, 1926-1990, Folders 21-30 of 33 (Box RCD 146)
      - Minutes and Related Documents, 1926-1990, Folders 31-33 of 33 (Box RCD 147)
      - Minutes and Related Documents, 1980-1999, 7 folders (Box RCD 152)
      - Recommendations of the Durham Committee, 1953-1958, 6 folders (Box RCD 147)
- Publications Series, 1910-2001 and undated, 9 boxes
  Includes annual and occasional publications published by The Duke Endowment, such as year books and annual reports; pamphlets about The Endowment's programs; manuals for the administration of hospitals and child care institutions; various editions of the indenture and deed of trust establishing The Duke Endowment; some publications collected by oral historian Frank W. Rounds for a biography of James B. Duke; and miscellaneous pamphlets and reprints. See also Oversize Materials.
  Arranged as Year Books, Annual Reports, Health Care Division, Child Care Division, Miscellaneous: Titles, and Miscellaneous: Authors. For those Health Care Division publications that have a bulletin number, the publications are arranged by the new titles used for the revised publications, not by the bulletin numbers.
  - Year Books
    - Nos. 1-23, 1928-1955 (Box PUB 1)
    - Form letter regarding Year Book No. 4, 1933 (Box PUB 1)
    - Nos. 24-26, 1956-1958 (Box PUB 2)
  - Annual Reports
    - The Duke Endowment, 1963-1991, 1993-1995, 1997-2001, and 2007 (Box PUB 2)
    - The Hospital Section, 1925-1939 (Box PUB 3)
    - The Orphan Section, 1925-1939 (Box PUB 4)
    - The Hospital and Orphan Sections, 1958-1962 (Box PUB 4)
  - Health Care Division [formerly Hospital Division]: (Box PUB 5)
    - Common Diagnoses, undated (Box PUB 5)
    - A Community Tribute to Marshall I. Pickens, 1968 (Box PUB 5)
    - The Duke Endowment Health Care Division: Facility Statistics for Long-Term Care, Fiscal Year 1998 (Box PUB 5)
    - The Duke Endowment Management Control Program: Report on Management Surveys, 1961 Feb. (Box PUB 5)
    - The Duke Endowment Management Control Program: Report on Work Sampling and Personnel Utilization, 1961 Oct. (Box PUB 5)
    - Evaluation of Computer Center for Forsyth Memorial Hospital and North Carolina Baptist Hospital, undated (Box PUB 5)
    - The Fair Labor Standards Act and Non-Federal Non-Profit Hospitals in South Carolina - A Study of Cost Impact, 1966 June (Box PUB 5)
    - Hospital Reports:, 26 folders
      - Aiken County Hospital, 1962 Dec. (Box PUB 5)
      - Anderson Memorial Hospital, 1964 May (Box PUB 5)
      - Charles A. Cannon, Jr. Memorial Hospital, 1962 June (Box PUB 5)
      - Charlotte Memorial Hospital, undated (Box PUB 5)
      - Charlotte Rehabilitation Hospital, 1961 Nov. (Box PUB 5)
      - Chesterfield County Memorial Hospital, 1963 July (Box PUB 5)
      - Colleton County Hospital, 1960 Aug. (Box PUB 5)
      - Columbia Hospital, 1963 Aug.-1964, Sept. (Box PUB 5)
      - Forsyth Memorial Hospital, 1962 July (Box PUB 5)
      - Gaston Memorial Hospital, 1960 Sept.-1964 July and undated (Box PUB 5)
      - Good Samaritan Hospital, 1962 Apr. and undated (Box PUB 5)
      - Grace Hospital, 1960 Sept. (Box PUB 5)
      - Greenville Central Hospital, 1960 Oct.-1963 May and undated, 3 folders (Box PUB 5)
      - Highsmith Memorial Hospital, 1961 Jan.-.1961 June and undated (Box PUB 5)
      - Kings Mountain Hospital, 1960 Sept. and undated (Box PUB 5)
      - Lexington Memorial Hospital, 1961 Mar. (Box PUB 6)
      - North Carolina Baptist Hospitals, Inc., 1959 Sept. and undated, 2 folders (Box PUB 6)
      - Presbyterian Hospital, 1910, 1960 Oct. and undated (Box PUB 6)
      - Rowan Memorial Hospital, 1960 Oct. and undated (Box PUB 6)
      - Scotland Memorial Hospital, 1962 Nov. (Box PUB 6)
      - Stanly County Hospital, 1960 Aug. and undated (Box PUB 7)
      - Watauga Hospital, 1961 June 29 (Box PUB 7)
      - York County Hospital, 1960 Aug. and undated (Box PUB 7)
    - Hospital Section Report Drafts: Policy and Procedures Manual, 1980, 3 folders (Box PUB 7)
    - Novus, 1990-1991 (Box PUB 7)
    - Procedures in Record Keeping for Hospitals, Bulletin No. 1, revised 1963 (Box PUB 7)
    - A Six-Year Review of the Activities of Assisted Tuberculosis Sanitoria in the Carolinas, 1930 (Box PUB 7)
    - The Small General Hospital, Bulletin No. 3, 1928, revised 1932 (Box PUB 7)
    - The Small General Hospital Organization and Management, Bulletin No. 4, 1934, revised 1947, 1960 (Box PUB 7)
    - The Small General Hospital Procedures in Record Keeping, Bulletin No. 1, 1942, revised 1948, 1956 (Box PUB 7)
    - A Study of Preadmission Techniques in General Hospitals of North Carolina and South Carolina, 1963 May (Box PUB 7)
    - SunHealth: Review and Future Implications of the Planning, Budgeting, and Clinical Management Project, 1984 Feb. (Box PUB 7)
    - A System of Hospital Accounting, Bulletin No. 1, 1926, revised 1929 (Box PUB 7)
    - The Therapy of Friendliness, 1962 Apr. (Box PUB 7)
  - Child Care Division:
    - Packet for Child Care Retreat on Children and Families, Graylyn Conferenece Center, Winston Salem, N.C., 1997 Jan. 15-16 (Box PUB 7)
    - Procedures in Record Keeping for Child-Caring Institutions, Bulletin No. 2, revised 1959 (Box PUB 7)
    - Sample Procedures in Record Keeping for Child-Caring Institutions:
      - Book I, 1959 (Box PUB 7)
      - Book II, General Ledger, 1959 (Box PUB 7)
    - A System of Accounting for Children's Homes, 1931 (Box PUB 7)
  - Miscellaneous: Titles: (Box PUB 8)
    - Battles of Kings Mountain 1780, and Cowans Ford 1781, As Described by General Joseph Graham, North Carolina University Magazine, (photocopy) 1856 (Box PUB 8)
    - The Charlotte Medical Journal, 1915 Sept. (Box PUB 8)
    - Determination by the Executors of James B. Duke, Deceased, 1927 (Box PUB 8)
    - The Duke Endowment press releases, 1960-1979, 4 folders (Box PUB 8)
    - The Duke Endowment: Spirit of Genius, Legacy of Hope, booklet and flyers, 2008, 2 copies of each title
      - The Duke Endowment: Spirit of Genius, Legacy of Hope (flyer) (Box PUB 8)
      - Focusing on Results (Box PUB 8)
      - Fortifying Leadership of Faith Communities (Box PUB 8)